Finding Aid for Kevin Duke Papers 1984-1998
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Kevin Duke Papers 1984-1998 1987-1997
Duke, Kevin.
1 linear ft.
Ann Arbor, Michigan, businessman, active in local community groups and programs; a founder of Trailblazers of Washtenaw County, a non-profit agency operating a clubhouse rehabilitation center for the mentally ill; also active in Ann Arbor educational issues. Records of Trailblazers include bylaws, minutes, publications, and other administrative records; also files relating to involvement in other organizations for the mentally ill and Ann Arbor education.
0224 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
This collection was the gift of Mr. Duke (donor no. 8269 ) and came to the library in 2001.
The records are open to research; names of individuals receiving services from Trailblazers may not be cited.
Kevin Duke is an Ann Arbor businessman and an active member of several local community groups. He graduated from the University of Michigan in 1980 with a bachelor's degree in English. In 1981, he started the Duke Realty Corporation. He is licensed as both a real estate agent and builder. Duke has also served as the president of the Halcyon II Corporation, a company that operates the Burwood House, an adult foster care home for the chronically mentally ill in Ann Arbor.
Duke has been a community activist in Ann Arbor and Washtenaw County for over twenty years. He has worked with a variety of community service programs, such as food banks, and he ran for 9th District Washtenaw County Commissioner in the early 1990s. Duke was especially interested in the development of local support groups and services for the mentally ill and their families. He was president of the Alliance for the Mentally Ill of Washtenaw County from 1989 to 1990, and he received Washtenaw Community College's 1990 Community Organization Award in recognition of the Alliance's work. Duke was also a founder of the Trailblazers of Washtenaw County, a non-profit agency operating a clubhouse rehabilitation center for the mentally ill. He served on its executive board from 1989 to 1998.
As a father, involvement in his children's education expanded his community interests to include educational issues. Duke served on two Ann Arbor Public School committees: the Equity Audit Committee (1993-1997), and the Wines Elementary School's School Management Team (1995-1997). He was appointed to the Equity Audit Committee by the Ann Arbor Board of Education, and he was elected as a parent representative to the Wines Elementary School Management Team.
The papers of Kevin Duke consist primarily of materials related to the different community service groups with which he was involved: Trailblazers of Washtenaw County, Alliance for the Mentally Ill in Washtenaw County, the Equity Audit Committee, and the Wines Elementary School's School Management Team. More than half of the collections relate to Trailblazers. The collection has been divided into two series: Trailblazers of Washtenaw County and Other Projects.
Subjects:
Alliance for the Mentally Ill of Washtenaw County.; Ann Arbor (Mich.); Duke, Kevin.; Education--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Mentally ill--Care--Michigan--Washtenaw County.; Schools--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Trailblazers of Washtenaw County.
- Trailblazers of Washtenaw County, 1989-1998
  - Trailblazers of Washtenaw County
    The Trailblazers of Washtenaw County series (1989-1998; .6 linear feet) documents the incorporation of the organization and Duke's involvement in his capacity as member of the executive board. Trailblazers' mission includes a dedication to providing a community-based rehabilitation center for adults experiencing the disabling effects of psychiatric illness, and it is committed to improving social services for persons with mental illness by developing vocational programs and a sense of community. Duke served on the executive board from 1989 to 1998. Materials in this series relate to regular board meetings, budgets, correspondence, fundraising, service project proposals, and building maintenance. Trailblazers discussed merging with the Full Circle Community Center and Project Transition in 1996-1997, and it eventually did merge with Full Circle in 1997. Three subseries have been created to reflect the three periods of administrative history: (1) Trailblazers alone, (2) Trailblazers plus Full Circle and Project Transition as the three agencies discussed merging, and (3) Trailblazers/Full Circle post-merger.
    - Bylaws, Administrative Structure, 1989-1996 (Box 1)
    - Agendas, Minutes, Reports, 1989-1997, 4 folders (Box 1)
    - Community Center Proposal, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Events, Publications, User Statistics, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
    - Personnel Letters, Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1994-1998 (Box 1)
    - Accreditation Requirements/Documentation, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
    - Buildings/Maintenance, 1987-1998, 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Trailblazers of Washtenaw County/Full Circle Community Center/Project Transition
    - Merger Agendas, Minutes, Reports, 1996-1997, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Trailblazers of Washtenaw County/Full Circle Community Center
    - Agendas, Minutes, Reports, 1997-1998 (Box 1)
    - Substance Abuse Services Proposal, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Fundraising, 1996-1998 (Box 1)
- Other Projects, 1984-1997
  The Other Projects series (1984-1997, .4 linear feet) includes files on other community groups or committees to which Duke contributed his time, as well as a file of newspaper clippings and political letters written by or to Duke. Materials in this series include a brief administrative file on the Alliance for the Mentally Ill of Washtenaw County, a file on the public debate surrounding the siting of Halcyon's Burwood House for mentally ill patients in a family neighborhood, and administrative records for the Ann Arbor Public School's Equity Audit Committee and Wines Elementary School's School Management Team. The Equity Audit Committee was responsible for monitoring progress made by Ann Arbor in ensuring equal educational opportunities for all students, particularly in the areas of the application of disciplinary policies and academic opportunities. The Wines School Management Team was responsible for working with the school's staff, teachers, students, and parents to develop acceptable standards for student behavior.
  - Alliance for the Mentally Ill of Washtenaw County, 1984-1997 (Box 1)
  - News Clippings, Letters, Political Correspondence, 1988-1997 (Box 1)
  - Proposed Group Home at 201 Burwood (Ann Arbor), 1987 (Box 1)
  - Equity Audit Committee (Ann Arbor Public Schools)
    - Orientation Notebook, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
    - Agendas, Minutes, Reports, 1993-1997, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Wines Elementary School (Ann Arbor) School Management Team, 1995-1997 (Box 1)